Sean Helvey Santa Barbara, CA

(714) 905-6742 | me@seanhelvey.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software engineer with experience in SAAS, e-commerce, AI, web, mobile, and cloud-based applications. Expertise in JavaScript. Equipped with strong technical skills and demonstrated aptitude for composing practical code that works and integrates well with existing components. Good at solving hard problems. Continuously learning new technologies while relying on the fundamentals.

- M.S. in Computer Science, New York University, 2012
- Certificate in Applied Data Science (Python Specialization), University of Michigan, In Progress
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, In Progress

<u>Front-End</u>	Back-End	<u>Data Science</u>
React	Node.js	Python
Vue.js	Koa	Jupyter
Gatsby	Express	NumPy
Next.js	PostgreSQL	Pandas
MobX	MySQL	D3.js
Redux	MongoDB	Docker

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Lull

March 2020 - September 2020

Goleta, CA

Managed continuous updates and upgrades on Lull's e-commerce platform, including integration of payment providers—PayPal, Verifi, Braintree, Apple Pay—and development of novel components using Vue.js. Managed continuous integration with TeamCity. Developed A/B Testing with Google Optimize & Optimizely.

Senior Software Engineer, AppFolio

April 2019 - March 2020

Goleta, CA

Created scalable, robust, and simple web-based software solutions for a leading property management SAAS company.

- Created visualizations for AppFolio's AI virtual leasing assistant.
- Integrated 3rd-party leasing provider, Blue Moon.
- Refactored sign-in application from 7 to 3 screens.
- Developed date/time component to automate scheduling.

Lead Instructor, Galvanize

July 2017 - March 2019

Boulder, CO

Lead instructor for an immersive web development bootcamp. Prepared eight cohorts of twenty students to become full stack developers.

- "Campus Captain" for Galvanize Boulder.
- Expanded and taught curricula on JavaScript, React, Redux, and Cloud Native Essentials.

Software Engineer, Pearson

November 2016 - July 2017

Boulder, CO

Built and maintained machine learning software to grade and report results for a leading testing company.

- Cut statistics processing time in half.
- Created dashboard visualizations displaying histograms used to train machine learning models.
- Developed numerous experiments using Jupyter/IPython notebooks and Docker containers.

LinkedIn: seanhelvey

Sean Helvey Page 2

Chief Technology Officer, Blue Hook

May 2014 - November 2016

Boulder, CO

Founded and led an independent software development consulting firm.

- Designed and developed web-based contractor portal for construction and property management company, Motili.
- Led a team of expert coders on a satellite imagery search engine project for Apollo Mapping, including development of a full stack application to enable front-end search result filtering.
- Built and tested custom components and data visualizations for KPMG.
- Optimized web-based flight reservation system for Hawaiian Airlines for accessibility by visual and hearing impaired users.

Software Engineer, Simple Energy

October 2013 - May 2014

Boulder, CO

Designed, built, and maintained web experiences to engage utility customers for a specialized SAAS company.

Software Engineer, Genscape

November 2012 - June 2013

Boulder, CO

Developed and maintained data collection and analysis system for natural gas pipeline production and market analysis software company.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, New York University

2012

- Emphasis in Databases and Natural Language Processing.
- Financial Software Development Intern at Bloomberg.
- Capstone project Smart thermostat development at EnergyHub.

Bachelor of Science in Business, Cal Poly San Luis Obispo

2006

- Concentration in Finance & Accounting.
- Fixed Income Research Intern at Allegiance Capital.
- Member of the Student Managed Portfolio Project.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer, Yoga Soup	2020 - Present
Volunteer, Best Day Foundation	2019 - Present
Coach, Techstars Startup Weekend	2019 - Present
Champion, CoderDojo Boulder	2014 - 2015
Event Volunteer, Boulder County Independent Business Alliance	2014 - 2015